Making an animated avatar is an
excellent way to add personalization to
faceless videos. You must have already
watched videos like this and this
getting tons of views and engagement. So
today I will show you step by step how
to create a talking animated avatar for
your faceless videos. And no, we are not
talking about any paid tools. And we
won't be making the character wear a
mask so its mouth can be hidden. Co is
long gone. mask would look awkward. Here
[music] we go. Stay tuned until the end
for a special bonus method. [music]
So, the first step is to choose a free
image generation tool like Adobe
Firefly. Open it on your browser and
sign up using your Google account. Now,
we need a detailed image prompt to use
in Firefly. For this, I use chat GPT. I
mention a few rough details. For
example, in this tutorial, I tell it
that the AI avatar will be a woman in
formal wear. She is facing forward and
straight. Now, use the chat GPT output
to generate the avatar in Firefly. It
generated four results. I am choosing
the one that looks like she has a
proportionate face and would fit the
required role. The second [music] step
is removing the mouth. For this, we can
go to cleanup pictures. On cleanup
pictures, we will upload the generated
avatar image. Do reduce the brush size
for precision. Carefully remove the
mouth. If the shade is dark and it is
not properly removed, go over and over.
I do realize it looks weird for now, but
it will be fixed in the following steps.
Now you can just remove the background
of the mouth video using Canva
background remover. I pasted the image
in Canva, overlaid the mouth video
without the background, and placed it in
the correct place. There you have it.
The talking AI avatar is ready. Just
download it, and you are good to go. It
might take some time to get the green
screen background removed neatly. You
can also use Cap Cut for better results.
You can try different mouth styles to
see which one fits the best. Now, as for
the bonus tip I promised, you can create
your talking animated characters even
more easily using Hedra. First, visit
hedra.com and sign up. Click on try
beta. You will see three columns, one of
audio, one of character, and one of
video. In the audio column, you put in
the script the avatar will speak and
select a voice. I will select a voice
that sounds like a friendly lady.
[music] In the character column, you can
either generate an AI image or upload an
existing image. Then in the video
column, click on generate video. And
voila, your talking AI avatar is ready.
Here is the sample that I created. I
first used the create option of the
character column. The character was
good, but I wanted to check it with an
existing image I had, so I used the one
I used previously. You can customize
your character as you like. Then save
and export your animated character.
Well, that is all for today. If you
enjoyed this tutorial, do like and
share. See you in the next